https://www.ameb.edu.au/contact/privacy-policy.html

Log In
Search:
Shop
Syllabuses & Study ResourcesManual of Syllabuses 2021Manual of Syllabuses 2020Digital Syllabuses 2021Digital Syllabuses 2020Digital Syllabuses 2019Digital Syllabuses 2018Recorded AccompanimentsAural TestsPractice DiaryManuscript & NotationAMEB VintageCentenary PublicationsVoiceSingingMusical TheatreSinging for LeisureCPM VocalRockschool VoiceKeyboard & PianoPianoPiano for LeisureCPM KeyboardP Plate PianoRockschool PianoTheory, Speech & TeachingTheory of MusicMusic CraftMusicianshipRockschool Music TheorySpeech & DramaTeachingDigital ResourcesRockschool Music ProductionPercussionPercussion - Grade BooksPercussion - Sight ReadingPercussion - Technical WorkPercussion - Recorded AccompanimentsCPM Drum KitRockschool DrumsStringsViolinViolaCelloDouble BassClassical GuitarRockschool GuitarCPM GuitarRockschool BassCPM BassRockschool Acoustic GuitarHarpWoodwindsFluteOboeClarinetSaxophoneSaxophone for LeisureBassoonRecorderBrassTrumpetHornTromboneEuphoniumTubaBandRockschoolRockschool PianoRockschool DrumsRockschool Music ProductionRockschool Acoustic GuitarRockschool VoiceRockschool BassRockschool GuitarRockschool Music TheoryRockschool Ukulele
Catalogue PDF
Shipping
Downloads
Preferred Retailers
Exams
ExamsPracticalWrittenSpeech & DramaTeachingRegulationsEnrol & Exam dates
Study
StudyOnline coursesPublicationsRecordingsScholarshipsTeachingP Plate Piano
About
AboutOnline OrchestraFAQsMediaFederal OfficeState OfficesBoard DirectorsExaminersOpportunities
Contact
ContactPrivacy PolicyTerms and ConditionsReturn and Refund Policy
Menu
Shop
Syllabuses & Study Resources Manual of Syllabuses 2021Manual of Syllabuses 2020Digital Syllabuses 2021Digital Syllabuses 2020Digital Syllabuses 2019Digital Syllabuses 2018Recorded AccompanimentsAural TestsPractice DiaryManuscript & NotationAMEB VintageCentenary PublicationsKeyboard & Piano PianoPiano for LeisureCPM KeyboardP Plate PianoRockschool PianoPercussion Percussion - Grade BooksPercussion - Sight ReadingPercussion - Technical WorkPercussion - Recorded AccompanimentsCPM Drum KitRockschool DrumsStrings ViolinViolaCelloDouble BassClassical GuitarRockschool GuitarCPM GuitarRockschool BassCPM BassRockschool Acoustic GuitarHarpWoodwinds FluteOboeClarinetSaxophoneSaxophone for LeisureBassoonRecorderBrass TrumpetHornTromboneEuphoniumTubaBandRockschool Rockschool PianoRockschool DrumsRockschool Music ProductionRockschool Acoustic GuitarRockschool VoiceRockschool BassRockschool GuitarRockschool Music TheoryRockschool UkuleleVoice SingingMusical TheatreSinging for LeisureCPM VocalRockschool VoiceTheory, Speech & Teaching Theory of MusicMusic CraftMusicianshipRockschool Music TheorySpeech & DramaTeachingDigital ResourcesRockschool Music Production
Exams
ExamsPracticalWrittenSpeech & DramaTeachingRegulationsEnrol & Exam dates
Study
StudyOnline coursesPublicationsRecordingsScholarshipsTeachingP Plate Piano
About
AboutFAQsFederal OfficeState OfficesBoard DirectorsExaminersOpportunitiesOnline OrchestraMedia
Contact
ContactPrivacy PolicyTerms and ConditionsReturn and Refund Policy
0
Checkout
You have no items in your shopping cart.
Make a Donation
You Are Here :
Home
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
The Australian Music Examinations Board [www.ameb.edu.au] web site (Web Site) is owned and operated by Australian Music Examinations Board Limited ACN 102 374 587 (AMEB). AMEB is committed to protecting the personal information and privacy of persons accessing this Web Site (You or Your).
AMEB is required to comply with the Australian Privacy Principles set out in the Privacy Act 1988.
By visiting and using this Web Site, You agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, as they may be amended from time to time. If You have any questions, or would like to provide feedback, please feel free to contact us on the number or address listed below.
The Privacy Practices of AMEB
1. What is personal information and what personal information do we collect?
‘Personal information’ means information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable, whether true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not.
The kinds of personal information AMEB collects may include Your name, email address, telephone number and address, and any other information You provide to us.
When collecting Your personal information, we will take reasonable steps to make You aware of the purposes for which we are collecting it, the types of organisations to which we would usually disclose it, whether we are likely to disclose it to overseas recipients (and where practicable the countries in which they are located), whether there are laws or court/tribunal orders which require or authorise us to collect it, and the main consequences for You if You fail to provide it to us.  This Privacy Policy provides these details as they typically apply in most cases, however different details may apply depending on our specific interaction with You.  If we do not notify You of such other details, the information in this Privacy Policy applies.
If You fail to provide personal information requested by us, there may be a range of consequences, for example we may be unable to provide our products or services to You or otherwise process or respond to Your request.  There will not usually be Australian laws or court/tribunal orders which require or authorise us to collect Your personal information.
2. How do we collect personal information?
We aim to collect personal information directly from You, for example, when You provide information through the online forms on our Web Site (such as when you register to create an account, post a submission on our Web Site or email us). We may also collect personal information:
from local Australian Music Examinations Board organisations based in the various Australian States and Territories (AMEB State Offices);
from publicly available sources of information; and
when we are permitted or required to do so by law (including the Privacy Act).
Any registration information You provide to Your AMEB State Office for the AMEB online examination (AMEB Online Examination) will be retained by AMEB as well as the AMEB State Office. Please be aware that all personal information collected from an AMEB State Office regarding the AMEB Online Examination will be subject to this Privacy Policy insofar as that personal information is collected by AMEB.
AMEB may also collect information about Your use of the Web Site such as what pages You visit and the Internet address You have come from.
Any further collection of Your personal information than that explained here will usually only occur with Your consent. 3. What are the purposes for which we collect, hold, use and disclose personal information?
Generally, AMEB will only use or disclose Your personal information for the purpose for which we collected it and for related purposes we consider will be within Your reasonable expectations.
We collect and use personal information:
to provide You with information, products or services You request;
to tailor Your experience of our Web Site to Your interests;
for marketing and survey purposes and to send You information about new features, products, content, promotional offers or additional goods or services that we consider may be of interest to You; and
to conduct contests, competitions, voting activities or community postings that You choose to participate in;
to provide service updates;
to meet legal and regulatory requirements;
to authorise and process customer transactions;
to detect and prevent fraud and other illegal uses of our services;
to develop, offer, and manage the various products and services provided by our company; and
to troubleshoot any problems we may have with our services.
If at any time You do not wish to receive any additional marketing information from us, please contact us and let us know. You may also be able to do this by using an unsubscribe facility that we provide in our communications to You.
4. How do we share personal information with others?
AMEB may disclose Your personal information to AMEB State Offices, and to Rockschool Ltd (Rockschool UK) where applicable. Other than as stated in this Privacy Policy, AMEB will not disclose Your personal information to any other third party, except when it has Your permission or under special circumstances, such as when the law requires or authorises disclosure or where You would reasonably expect disclosure for a related purpose, for example where it is necessary to provide You with a service which You have requested.
Like many businesses, AMEB uses a range of service providers to help us maximise the quality and efficiency of our services and our business operations. This means that individuals and organisations outside of AMEB, such as web hosting service providers, or third party contractors assisting us to conduct our marketing and survey activities, will sometimes have access to personal information held by AMEB and may use it on behalf of AMEB. We require our service providers to adhere to strict privacy guidelines and not to keep this information or use it for any unauthorised purposes.
AMEB may also use and disclose pooled information obtained about visitors to our web site to understand our users’ interests and improve our services. These reports may be shared with the partners and sponsors of AMEB but they will not disclose personally identifiable information.5. Cross-border disclosure of Your personal information
Generally, AMEB is unlikely to disclose Your personal information to a third party outside of Australia (Overseas Recipient), other than Rockschool UK. However, it is possible that an AMEB service provider (of a kind described under heading 4 above) may be an Overseas Recipient.
If however You consent to the disclosure of Your personal information to an Overseas Recipient, You understand and agree that the Overseas Recipient may not be required to comply with the Australian Privacy Principles, and that AMEB may not take steps to ensure that the Overseas Recipient handles Your personal information in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles. AMEB will not be responsible for, or otherwise liable for the way in which, the Overseas Recipient handles Your personal information.
4. How can You access or update Your personal information?
AMEB will try to ensure that Your personal information is kept up to date, complete and as accurate as possible and may from time to time contact You to confirm this or request You to update Your details.
If at any time You want to know what personal information we hold about You, You are welcome to access Your record by emailing us at office@ameb.edu.au. We will, except in special circumstances, make Your personal information available to You subject to any identity verification checks and (depending on scope of Your request) the payment of the fee (if any) we notify You for us to provide such access.
If You lodge a request for access, we may provide You with access to Your personal information in any of a number of ways (including, for example, supplying You with a copy of Your personal information, or providing You with the opportunity to view Your personal information).
If You establish that any personal information we hold about You is not accurate, complete and up-to-date, to our reasonable satisfaction, we will amend our records accordingly. Please notify us if Your personal details change so that we may keep our records up-to-date.5. Our Web Site privacy practices
We sometimes use cookie technology on our Web Site. Cookies are pieces of information that a Web Site transfers to Your computer for tracking purposes and can be used to customise a Web Site experience and facilitate online transactions. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. AMEB uses cookies for purposes such as to make Your use of our Web Site and services as enjoyable as possible. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they can identify a user’s browser. Cookies are useful to estimate our number of members and determine overall traffic patterns through our Web Site, as well as responding to Your requests for particular services.
If You do not wish to receive any cookies You may set Your browser to refuse cookies. This may mean You will not be able to take full advantage of AMEB services.
You must ensure that Your browser is set to accept cookies in order to use certain functionality of the AMEB Web Sites (such as AMEB’s online examinations, online shop and Rockschool site).6. Automatic server logs
Our Web Site server automatically collects various items of information when You use our Web Site, including:
Your IP (“Internet Protocol”) address (which, in general terms, is a unique identifier assigned to Your computer when it is connected to the internet);
the operating system and internet browser software You are currently using; and
the data that You download (such as web pages or other document files or software), and the time that You download it.
Although, in some circumstances, it may be possible to identify You from this information, we do not attempt to do so, and only use this information for statistical analysis, system administration, and similar related purposes. This information is not disclosed to any other party.8. Links to other sitesIf any of our online services (including any email messages we send to You) contain links to other online services that are not maintained by us (Other Services), or if Other Services link to our online services, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of the organisations that operate those other services, and by providing such links we do not endorse or approve the other services. This Privacy Policy applies only in respect of AMEB. 9. Storage and security
AMEB will endeavour to take reasonable steps to ensure Your personal information is kept secure, accurate and up-to-date. Your information is stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. So, while AMEB make use of available technology, such as encryption software, to protect Your personal information, AMEB cannot give an absolute assurance that the information You provide to AMEB will be secure at all times. You accordingly provide such information at Your own risk and AMEB will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to Your personal information.
If a data breach or suspected data breach occurs, we will undertake a prompt investigation, which will include an assessment of whether the incident is likely to result in serious harm to any individuals. In such a situation we will comply with the requirements of the Privacy Act which may require notification to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC) and affected individuals. Please contact us if You have reason to believe or suspect that a data breach may have occurred, so that we can investigate and, if necessary, undertake appropriate containment, risk mitigation and notification activities as required.
10. Making a complaint
You may lodge a complaint with us if You believe we have handled Your personal information other than in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles. To do so please contact us using the details set out below. We will confirm receipt of Your complaint and set out the timeframe we require to investigate Your complaint and provide You with a response. We will endeavour to respond as quickly as possible, generally within 30 days of receiving Your complaint.Contact us:If You have questions about our Privacy Policy and practices, would like to provide feedback or would like to access or correct Your personal information held by us, please contact us.
Email:
office@ameb.edu.au
Mail:Australian Music Examinations BoardPrivacy OfficerLevel 821 Victoria StreetMelbourne Vic 3000
Future ChangesAMEB will continue to evolve as we introduce new services and features to our Web Site. Because of this, from time to time, our policies will be reviewed and may be revised. AMEB reserves the right to change its Privacy Policy at any time and post an updated version on the Web Site. If You object to any changes, You may discontinue Your use of the services. The amended Privacy Policy will apply between AMEB and You whether or not we have given You specific notice of any change.
Last revised: 5 March 2018
Copyright © 2018 Australian Music Examinations Board Limited. All rights reserved
Contact
Contact Privacy Policy Terms and Conditions Return and Refund Policy
AMEB Ltd. Level 8, 21 Victoria StreetMelbourne VIC 3000 Telephone 1300 725 709 online@ameb.edu.au
Help Us to Keep Magento Healthy - Report All Bugs (ver. 1.8.1.0)
All prices are in Australian Dollars and include GST | Terms & Privacy
©
Australian Music Examinations Board | ABN 27102374587
Choose charity:
Yugambeh Youth Choir donations
Remove donation
Donation amount:
Donate
Minimum donation $2.00
